<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
Copyright 2016, 2017 Institut National de la Recherche Agronomique

Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
You may obtain a copy of the License at

        http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
limitations under the License.
-->

<alvisnlp-doc author="Robert Bossy" date="2010-10-28">
  <synopsis>
    <p>Reads files and adds a document in the corpus for each file.</p>
  </synopsis>

  <module-doc>
    <description>
      <p><this/> reads file(s) from <param name="sourcePath"/> and creates a document in the corpus for each file. The identifier of the created document is the absolute path of the corresponding file. The created document has a single section named <param name="section"/> whose contents is the contents of the corresponding file.</p>
      <p>If <param name="sourcePath"/> is a path to a file, then <this/> will read this file. If <param name="sourcePath"/> is a path to a directory, then <this/> will read the files in this directory. If <param name="recursive"/> is set to true, then the files in sub-directories will be read recursively. <this/> only reads files whose name match <param name="acceptPattern"/>. If <param name="acceptPattern"/> is not set, then <this/> reads all files.</p>
      <p>If <param name="linesLimit"/> is set, then <this/> creates a new document for each set of lines. For instance, if <param name="linesLimit"/> is set to 10 and a file contains 25 lines, then 3 documents are created: two containing 10 lines and one containing the las 5 lines.</p>
      <p>Files are read using the same encoding <param name="charset"/>.</p>
      <p>The created documents will all have the features defined in <param name="constantDocumentFeatures"/>. The unique section will have the features defined in <param name="constantSectionFeatures"/>.</p>
    </description>
  
    <param-doc name="constantDocumentFeatures">
      <p>Constant features to add to each document created by this module</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="active">
      <p>This expression is evaluated as a boolean with the corpus as the context element, the module will process the document only if the result is true.</p>
    </param-doc>
      
    <param-doc name="charset">
      <p>Character set of the input files.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="constantSectionFeatures">
      <p>Constant features to add to each section created by this module</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="linesLimit">
      <p>Maximum number of lines per document.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="sourcePath">
      <p>Path to the source directory or source file.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="sectionName">
      <p>Name of the single section containing the whole contents of a file.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="sizeLimit">
      <p>Maximum number of characters per document. No limit if not set.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="baseNameId">
      <p>Use the filename base name instead of the full path as document identifier.</p>
    </param-doc>
  <param-doc name="userFunctions"><p>Set user functions available for this module. If this module is a sequence, then all compounds inherit its functions.</p></param-doc></module-doc>
</alvisnlp-doc>
