<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
Copyright 2016, 2017 Institut National de la Recherche Agronomique

Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
You may obtain a copy of the License at

        http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
limitations under the License.
-->
<alvisnlp-doc author="" date="" target="fr.inra.maiage.bibliome.alvisnlp.bibliomefactory.modules.trie.OBOProjector">

  <synopsis>
    <p>Projects OBO terms and synonyms on sections.</p>
  </synopsis>

  <module-doc>
    <description>
      <p><this/> reads <param>source</param> SKOS terminologies or OWL ontologies and searches for class and concept labels in sections.</p>
      <p>The parameters <param>allowJoined</param>, <param>allUpperCaseInsensitive</param>, <param>caseInsensitive</param>, <param>ignoreDiacritics</param>, <param>joinDash</param>, <param>matchStartCaseInsensitive</param>, <param>skipConsecutiveWhitespaces</param>, <param>skipWhitespace</param> and <param>wordStartCaseInsensitive</param> control the matching between the section and the entry keys.</p>
      <p>The <param>subject</param> parameter specifies which text of the section should be matched. There are two options:
      <ul>
	<li>the entries are matched on the contents of the section, <param>subject</param> can also control if matches boundaries coincide with word delimiters;</li>
	<li>the entries are matched on the feature value of annotations of a given layer separated by a whitespace, in this way entries can be searched against word lemmas for instance.</li>
      </ul>
      </p>
      <p><this/> creates an annotation for each matched entry and adds these annotations to the layer named <param>targetLayerName</param>. The created annotations will have the feature <param>uriFeature</param> containing the URI of the matched class or concept. <this/> may also map property object values into features specified by <param>labelFeatures</param>.</p>
    </description>

    <param-doc name="source">
      <p>Path to the source SKOS/OWL files.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="labelFeatures">
      <p>Mapping from feature names to property URIs. This parameter indicates the properties of the entry to record in features.</p>
    </param-doc>

    <param-doc name="labelURIs">
      <p>RDF properties whose object values that represent entry keys.</p>
    </param-doc>

    <param-doc name="resourceTypeURIs">
      <p>Type of RDF resources that represent an entry.</p>
    </param-doc>

    <param-doc name="uriFeature">
      <p>Feature where to store the entry URI.</p>
    </param-doc>

    <param-doc name="uriFeatureName">
      <p>Deprecated alias for <param>uriFeature</param>.</p>
    </param-doc>
    
    <param-doc name="prefixes">
      <p>Specify URI prefixes to be used in <param>resourceTypeURIs</param>, <param>labelURIs</param>, and <param>labelFeatures</param></p>
    </param-doc>
    
    <param-doc name="rdfFormat">
      <p>Specify the RDF serialization format (xml, rdfxml, xmlrdf, turtle, ttl, n3, ntriples, ntriple, nt, jsonld, rdfjson, jsonrdf, json, trig, nquads, nq, nthrift, csv, tsv, trix).</p>
    </param-doc>
    
    <param-doc name="language">
      <p>Specify the language of labels to project. If this parameter is not set then labels of any language are projected. Labels without a language qualifier are always projected regardless of the value of this parameter.</p>
    </param-doc>

	<include-doc>fr.inra.maiage.bibliome.alvisnlp.bibliomefactory.modules.trie.TrieProjectorParamsDoc</include-doc>
  </module-doc>
</alvisnlp-doc>
