<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<alvisnlp-doc author="" beta="false" date="" short-target="YateaTermsProjector" target="YateaTermsProjector">
  <synopsis>
    <p>Search in the sections content for terms extracted by YaTeA (see <module>YateaExtractor</module>).</p>
  </synopsis>
  <module-doc>
    <description>
      <p><this/> reads terms in a YaTeA XML output file produced by <module>YateaExtractor</module> and searches for terms in section contents, or whatever specified by <param>subject</param>.</p>
      <p>The parameters <param>allowJoined</param>, <param>allUpperCaseInsensitive</param>, <param>caseInsensitive</param>, <param>ignoreDiacritics</param>, <param>joinDash</param>, <param>matchStartCaseInsensitive</param>, <param>skipConsecutiveWhitespaces</param>, <param>skipWhitespace</param> and <param>wordStartCaseInsensitive</param> control how the keys can match the sections content.</p>
      <p>The <param>subject</param> parameter specifies which text of the section should be matched. There are two alternatives:
      <ul>
	<li>the entries are matched on the contents of the section (the default), <param>subject</param> can also control if matches boundaries coincide with word delimiters;</li>
	<li>the entries are matched on the value of a specified feature of annotations in a given layer separated by a whitespace, in this way entries can be searched against word lemmas, for instance.</li>
      </ul>
      </p>
      <p><this/> creates an annotation for each matched key and adds these annotations to the layer specified by <param>targetLayer</param>. Term structure information can be recorded in the features specified by <param>termIdFeature</param>, <param>headFeature</param>, <param>monoHeadIdFeature</param>, <param>modifierFeature</param>, and <param>termPosFeature</param>. In addition, the created annotations will have the constant features specified in <param>constantAnnotationFeatures</param>.</p>
      <p><param>trieSource</param> and <param>trieSink</param> are not supported by <this/>.</p>
    </description>
    
    <param-doc name="head">
      <p>Deprecated alias for <param>headFeature</param>.</p>
    </param-doc>
    
    <param-doc name="modifier">
      <p>Deprecated alias for <param>modifierFeature</param>.</p>
    </param-doc>
    
    <param-doc name="monoHeadId">
      <p>Deprecated alias for <param>monoHeadIdFeature</param>.</p>
    </param-doc>
    
    <param-doc name="termId">
      <p>Deprecated alias for <param>termIdFeature</param>.</p>
    </param-doc>
    
    <param-doc name="termLemma">
      <p>Deprecated alias for <param>termLemmaFeature</param>.</p>
    </param-doc>
    
    <param-doc name="termPOS">
      <p>Deprecated alias for <param>termPosFeature</param>.</p>
    </param-doc>
    
    <param-doc name="headFeature">
      <p>Feature where to record the matched term's head identifier.</p>
    </param-doc>
    
    <param-doc name="modifierFeature">
      <p>Feature where to record the matched term's modifier identifier.</p>
    </param-doc>
    
    <param-doc name="monoHeadIdFeature">
      <p>Feature where to record the matched term's mono-head (or superhead, or single-token head) identifier.</p>
    </param-doc>
    
    <param-doc name="termIdFeature">
      <p>Feature where to record the matched term's identifier.</p>
    </param-doc>
    
    <param-doc name="termLemmaFeature">
      <p>Feature where to record the matched term's lemma string.</p>
    </param-doc>
    
    <param-doc name="termPosFeature">
      <p>Feature where to record the matched term's components POS tags.</p>
    </param-doc>
    
    <param-doc name="mnpOnly">
      <p>If <em>true</em>, then <this/> only searches for MNP terms.</p>
    </param-doc>
    
    <param-doc name="projectLemmas">
      <p>If <em>true</em>, the this searches for term lemmas instead of surface forms.</p>
    </param-doc>
    
    <param-doc name="yateaFile">
      <p>YaTeA output XML file, as produced by <module>YateaExtractor</module>.</p>
    </param-doc>

	<include-doc>fr.inra.maiage.bibliome.alvisnlp.bibliomefactory.modules.trie.TrieProjectorParamsDoc</include-doc>
  </module-doc>
</alvisnlp-doc>
