<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
Copyright 2016, 2017 Institut National de la Recherche Agronomique

Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
You may obtain a copy of the License at

        http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
limitations under the License.
-->

<alvisnlp-doc author="Robert Bossy" date="2010-10-28">
  <synopsis>
    <p>Detects sentence boundaries and creates one annotation for each sentence.</p>
    <p>This module assumes WoSMig processed the same sections.</p>
  </synopsis>

  <module-doc>
    <description>
      <p><this/> scans for annotations in <param name="wordLayerName"/> and detects a sentence boundaries defined as either:
      <ul>
	<li>an annotation whose feature <param name="eosStatusFeature"/> equals <em>eos</em>;</li>
	<li>an annotation whose surface form contains only characaters of the value of <param name="strongPunctuations"/> and which is followed by an uppercase character;</li>
	<li>an annotation whose feature <param name="eosStatusFeature"/> equals <em>maybe-eos</em> and which is followed by an uppercase character.</li>
      </ul>
      </p>
      <p><this/> creates an annotation for each sentence and adds it into the <param name="targetLayerName"/>. The <param name="eosStatusFeature"/> of word annotations are given a new value:
      <ul>
	<li><strong>eos</strong>: for the last word of each sentence;</li>
	<li><strong>not-eos</strong>: for all other words.</li>
      </ul>
      </p>
      <p>If <param name="noBreakLayerName"/> is defined, then <this/> will prevent sentence boundaries inside annotations in this layer.</p>
    </description>
  
    <param-doc name="constantAnnotationFeatures">
      <p>Constant features to add to each annotation created by this module</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="strongPunctuations">
      <p>List of strong punctuations.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="typeFeature">
      <p>Name of the feature where to read word annotation type.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="active">
      <p>This expression is evaluated as a boolean with the corpus as the context element, the module will process the document only if the result is true.</p>
    </param-doc>
      
    <param-doc name="wordLayerName">
      <p>Name of the layer containing word annotations.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="documentFilter">
      <p>Only process document that satisfy this filter.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="eosStatusFeature">
      <p>Name of the feature (in words) containing the end-of-sentence status (not-eos, maybe-eos).</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="sectionFilter">
      <p>Process only sections that satisfy this filter.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="formFeature">
      <p>Name of the feature containing the word surface form.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="noBreakLayerName">
      <p>Name of the layer containing annotations within which there cannot be sentence boundaries.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="targetLayerName">
      <p>Name of the layer where to store sentence annotations.</p>
    </param-doc>
  <param-doc name="userFunctions"><p>Set user functions available for this module. If this module is a sequence, then all compounds inherit its functions.</p></param-doc></module-doc>
</alvisnlp-doc>
