<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
Copyright 2016, 2017 Institut National de la Recherche Agronomique

Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
You may obtain a copy of the License at

        http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
limitations under the License.
-->
<alvisnlp-doc author="" date="" target="fr.inra.maiage.bibliome.alvisnlp.bibliomefactory.modules.trie.OBOProjector">

  <synopsis>
    <p>Projects OBO terms and synonyms on sections.</p>
  </synopsis>

  <module-doc>
    <description>
      <p><this/> reads <param>oboFiles</param> in <a href="XXX">OBO format</a> and searches for term names and synonyms in sections.</p>
      <p>The parameters <param>allowJoined</param>, <param>allUpperCaseInsensitive</param>, <param>caseInsensitive</param>, <param>ignoreDiacritics</param>, <param>joinDash</param>, <param>matchStartCaseInsensitive</param>, <param>skipConsecutiveWhitespaces</param>, <param>skipWhitespace</param> and <param>wordStartCaseInsensitive</param> control the matching between the section and the entry keys.</p>
      <p>The <param>subject</param> parameter specifies which text of the section should be matched. There are two options:
      <ul>
	<li>the entries are matched on the contents of the section, <param>subject</param> can also control if matches boundaries coincide with word delimiters;</li>
	<li>the entries are matched on the feature value of annotations of a given layer separated by a whitespace, in this way entries can be searched against word lemmas for instance.</li>
      </ul>
      </p>
      <p><this/> creates an annotation for each matched entry and adds these annotations to the layer named <param>targetLayerName</param>. The created annotations will have features <param>nameFeature</param>, <param>idFeature</param> and <param>pathFeature</param> set to the matched term name, identifier and path.</p>
      <p>If specified, then <this/> assumes that <param>trieSource</param> contains a compiled version of the dictionary. <param>oboFiles</param> is not read. If specified, <this/> writes a compiled version of the dictionary in <param>trieSink</param>. The use of compiled dictionaries may accelerate the processing for large dictionaries.</p>
    </description>
  
    <param-doc name="oboFiles">
      <p>Path to the source OBO files.</p>
    </param-doc>
    
    <param-doc name="idFeature">
      <p>Feature where to store the matched term identifier.</p>
    </param-doc>
     
    <param-doc name="nameFeature">
      <p>Feature where to store the matched term name.</p>
    </param-doc>
    
    <param-doc name="pathFeature">
      <p>Feature where to store the matched term path.</p>
    </param-doc>
   
    <param-doc name="keepDBXref">
      <p>Add all database cross-references of the term. <this/> creates a feature key-value pair for each <em>dbxref</em> in the matching term.</p>
    </param-doc>
   
    <param-doc name="versionFeature">
      <p>Name of the feature where to store the ontology version.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="ancestorsFeature">
      <p>Name of the feature that contains the term ancestors ids.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="childrenFeature">
      <p>Name of the feature that contains the term children ids.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="parentsFeature">
      <p>Name of the feature that contains the term parents ids.</p>
    </param-doc>

	<include-doc>fr.inra.maiage.bibliome.alvisnlp.bibliomefactory.modules.trie.TrieProjectorParamsDoc</include-doc>
</module-doc>
</alvisnlp-doc>
