<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
Copyright 2016, 2017 Institut National de la Recherche Agronomique

Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
You may obtain a copy of the License at

        http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
limitations under the License.
-->

<alvisnlp-doc author="" date="" target="fr.inra.maiage.bibliome.alvisnlp.bibliomefactory.modules.trie.XLSProjector">
  <synopsis>
    <p>Projects rows in XLS or XLSX files on sections.</p>
  </synopsis>

  <module-doc>
    <description>
      <p><this/> reads <param name="xlsFile"/> in Microsoft Excel XLS or XLSX formats and searches for row entries in sections.</p>
      <p>The parameters <param name="allowJoined"/>, <param name="allUpperCaseInsensitive"/>, <param name="caseInsensitive"/>, <param name="ignoreDiacritics"/>, <param name="joinDash"/>, <param name="matchStartCaseInsensitive"/>, <param name="skipConsecutiveWhitespaces"/>, <param name="skipWhitespace"/> and <param name="wordStartCaseInsensitive"/> control the matching between the section and the entry keys.</p>
      <p>The <param name="subject"/> parameter specifies which text of the section should be matched. There are two options:
      <ul>
	<li>the entries are matched on the contents of the section, <param name="subject"/> can also control if matches boundaries coincide with word delimiters;</li>
	<li>the entries are matched on the feature value of annotations of a given layer separated by a whitespace, in this way entries can be searched against word lemmas for instance.</li>
      </ul>
      </p>
      <p><this/> creates an annotation for each matched row and adds these annotations to the layer named <param name="targetLayerName"/>. The created annotations will have features whose keys correspond to <param name="valueFeatures"/> and values to the data associated to the matched entry (columns in the XLS file). For instance if <param name="valueFeatures"/> is <em>[a,b,c]</em>, then each annotation will have three features named <em>a</em>, <em>b</em> and <em>c</em> with the respective values of the entry's second, third and fourth columns. A feature name left blank in <param name="entryFeatureNames"/> will not create a feature. Thus, in order not to keep the entry in the <em>a</em> feature, <param name="entryFeatureNames"/> should be <em>[,b,c]</em>. In addition, the created annotations will have the feature keys and values defined in <param name="constantAnnotationFeatures"/>.</p>
      <p>If specified, then <this/> assumes that <param name="trieSource"/> contains a compiled version of the dictionary. <param name="dictFile"/> is not read. If specified, <this/> writes a compiled version of the dictionary in <param name="trieSink"/>. The use of compiled dictionaries may accelerate the processing for large dictionaries.</p>
    </description>

    <param-doc name="valueFeatures">
      <p>Target features in match annotations. The values are the columns in the matched entry line.</p>
    </param-doc>
    
    <param-doc name="headerRow">
    	<p>Either to skip the first row of each sheet.</p>
    </param-doc>
    
    <param-doc name="sheets">
    	<p>Index of the sheets to apply (starting at 0).</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="keyIndex">
      <p>Specifies the key column index (starting at 0).</p>
    </param-doc>
    
    <param-doc name="xlsFile">
      <p>Path to the source XLS files.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
	<include-doc>fr.inra.maiage.bibliome.alvisnlp.bibliomefactory.modules.trie.TrieProjectorParamsDoc</include-doc>
</module-doc>
</alvisnlp-doc>
