<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
Copyright 2016, 2017 Institut National de la Recherche Agronomique

Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
You may obtain a copy of the License at

        http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
limitations under the License.
-->

<alvisnlp-doc author="Robert Bossy" date="2012-04-30" target="org.bibliome.alvisnlp.modules.shell.Shell">
  <synopsis>
    <p>Starts an interactive shell that allows to query the corpus data structure.</p>
  </synopsis>

  <module-doc>
    <description>
      <p><this/> starts an interactive shell. The user may issue commands in order to explore the state of the corpus.</p>
      <h3>Shell commands</h3>
      <p>
	<xverb>@query expression</xverb><br/>
	Evaluates <em>expression</em> with the current element as the context element and prints the result. The shell attempts to determine the priviledged type of the expression, if the type could not be determined, the the user must coerce it with one of the type coercion expressions. If the result is a list of elements then a short summary of each element is printed on screen.
      </p>
      <p>
	<xverb>@allow everything|delete|args|features</xverb><br/>
	<xverb>@allow create all|documents|sections|relations|tuples|annotations</xverb><br/>
	Allows action expressions in query commands.
      </p>
      <p>
	<xverb>@features [expression]</xverb><br/>
	Evaluates <em>expression</em> as a list of elements, then prints all features for each element in the result. If <em>expression</em> is omitted, then prints all features of the current element.
      </p>
      <p>
	<xverb>@ref name expression</xverb><br/>
	Evaluates <em>expression</em>, then assigns the result to the reference <em>name</em>. This reference is accessible to all expressions in subsequent commands.
      </p>
      <p>
	<xverb>@move expression</xverb><br/>
	Evaluates <em>expression</em> as a list of elements. If the result is not empty, then the shell sets the current element to the first element of the result. <this/> keeps track of all <em>@move</em> commands in a stack, the following commands allow to navigate through this stack.
      </p>
      <p>
	<xverb>@next</xverb><br/>
	Sets the current element to the next element in the result list of the last <em>@move</em> command. If the current element was the last element, then this command does nothing.
      </p>
      <p>
	<xverb>@prev</xverb><br/>
	Sets the current element to the previous element in the result list of the last <em>@move</em> command. If the current element was the first element, then this command does nothing.
      </p>
      <p>
	<xverb>@up</xverb><br/>
	Sets the current element to the current element in the result of the <em>@move</em> command before the last one. If the last <em>@move</em> command was the first in the shell session, then this command sets the current element to the corpus.
      </p>
      <p>
	<xverb>@stack</xverb><br/>
	This command prints the current element of all <em>@move</em> commands in order of execution.
      </p>
      <p>
	<xverb>@state</xverb><br/>
	This command prints which action expressions are allowed in the current session, as well as all defined references.
      </p>
    </description>
  
    <param-doc name="active">
      <p>This expression is evaluated as a boolean with the corpus as the context element, the module will process the document only if the result is true.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="prompt">
      <p>Specifies the shell prompt.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="constantAnnotationFeatures">
      <p>Constant features to add to each annotation created by this module</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="constantDocumentFeatures">
      <p>Constant features to add to each document created by this module</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="constantRelationFeatures">
      <p>Constant features to add to each relation created by this module</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="constantSectionFeatures">
      <p>Constant features to add to each section created by this module</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="constantTupleFeatures">
      <p>Constant features to add to each tuple created by this module</p>
    </param-doc>
         
    <param-doc name="historyFile">
      <p>Path to the command history file.</p>
    </param-doc>
  <param-doc name="userFunctions"><p>Set user functions available for this module. If this module is a sequence, then all compounds inherit its functions.</p></param-doc></module-doc>
</alvisnlp-doc>
