<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
Copyright 2016, 2017 Institut National de la Recherche Agronomique

Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
You may obtain a copy of the License at

        http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
limitations under the License.
-->

<alvisnlp-doc author="Robert Bossy" date="2010-10-28">
  <synopsis>
    <p>Reads a corpus in XML files.</p>
  </synopsis>

  <module-doc>
    <description>
      <p><this/> reads a corpus in the file(s) <param name="sourcePath"/>. These files must be in the corpus XML serialization format (see <a href="alvisnlp-corpus.dtd">alvisnlp-corpus.dtd</a>). The file may be in any XML format as long as a proper XSLT transform is given by <param name="xslTransform"/>; the result of this stylesheet must be a valid corpus XML serialization. The string parameters defined in <param name=""/> are passed to the stylesheet.</p>
      <p>If <param name="sourcePath"/> is a path to a file, then <this/> will read this file. If <param name="sourcePath"/> is a path to a directory, then <this/> will read the files in this directory. If <param name="recursive"/> is set to true, then the files in sub-directories will be read recursively. <this/> only reads files whose name match <param name="acceptPattern"/>. If <param name="acceptPattern"/> is not set, then <this/> reads all files.</p>
      <p>The created documents, sections, annotations, relations and tuples will have the features defined in <param name="constantDocumentFeatures"/>, <param name="constantSectionFeatures"/>, <param name="constantAnnotationFeatures"/>, <param name="constantRelationFeatures"/> and <param name="constantTupleFeatures"/> respectively.</p>
    </description>
  
    <param-doc name="xslTransform">
      <p>XSLT stylesheet. Allows to read arbitrary XML files by transforming into the document serialization format.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="constantAnnotationFeatures">
      <p>Constant features to add to each annotation created by this module</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="constantDocumentFeatures">
      <p>Constant features to add to each document created by this module</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="active">
      <p>This expression is evaluated as a boolean with the corpus as the context element, the module will process the document only if the result is true.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="constantRelationFeatures">
      <p>Constant features to add to each relation created by this module</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="stringParams">
      <p>String parameters for the XSLT stylesheet.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="constantSectionFeatures">
      <p>Constant features to add to each section created by this module</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="sourcePath">
      <p>Path to the source directory or source file.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="constantTupleFeatures">
      <p>Constant features to add to each tuple created by this module</p>
    </param-doc>
  <param-doc name="userFunctions"><p>Set user functions available for this module. If this module is a sequence, then all compounds inherit its functions.</p></param-doc></module-doc>
</alvisnlp-doc>
