<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<alvisnlp-doc author="" beta="true" date="" short-target="PythonScript" target="fr.inra.maiage.bibliome.alvisnlp.bibliomefactory.modules.python.PythonScript">
  <synopsis>
    <p>Runs a Python script. This module is useful for processing the corpus with Python libraries dedicated to NLP.</p>
  </synopsis>

  <module-doc>
    <description>
      <p><this/> assumes the script reads from standard input the AlvisNLP data structure serialized as JSON. <this/> also assumes the script writes the modifications serialized in JSON to the standard output.</p>
      <p>The <code>alvisnlp.py</code> library facilitates the deserialization, serialization, and manipulation of the AlvisNLP data structure. It is located in the directory specified by <param>alvisnlpPythonDirectory</param>.</p>
      <p>The script to run is specified with <param>script</param>.</p>
    </description>

    <param-doc name="callPython">
      <p>Either to call Python interpreter as executable and the script as the command. If this parameter is <code>false</code>, then the user must have execution rights on the script, and the script must have the appropriate shebang to locate the Python interpreter.</p>
    </param-doc>
    
    <param-doc name="commandLine">
      <p>Additional command line arguments to pass to the script.</p>
    </param-doc>
    
    <param-doc name="layerNames">
      <p>Deprecated alias for <param>layers</param>.</p>
    </param-doc>
        
    <param-doc name="layers">
      <p>Names of layers to serialize. Layers not mentioned in this parameter will not be serialized. Use this to limit the amount of serialized data. By default <this/> serializes all annotations in all layers.</p>
    </param-doc>
    
    <param-doc name="relations">
      <p>Names of relations to serialize. Relations not mentioned in this parameter will not be serialized. Use this to limit the amount of serialized data. By default <this/> serializes all tuples in all relations.</p>
    </param-doc>
    
    <param-doc name="relationNames">
      <p>Deprecated alias for <param>relations</param>.</p>
    </param-doc>
    
    <param-doc name="script">
      <p>Path to the script to run.</p>
    </param-doc>
    
    <param-doc name="scriptParams">
      <p>Parameters to pass through the the serialized data structure. Expressions are evaluated from the corpus as strings.</p>
    </param-doc>
    
    <include-doc>fr.inra.maiage.bibliome.alvisnlp.bibliomefactory.modules.python.PythonScriptBaseParamsDoc</include-doc>
  </module-doc>
</alvisnlp-doc>
