<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
Copyright 2016, 2017 Institut National de la Recherche Agronomique

Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
You may obtain a copy of the License at

        http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
limitations under the License.
-->

<alvisnlp-doc author="Mouhamadou Ba" date="2012-03-21" target="org.bibliome.alvisnlp.modules.tees.TEESClassify">
  <synopsis>
    <p> recognize and classify chemicals in natural language texts</p>
  </synopsis>

  <module-doc>
    <description>
      <p> ChemSpot 2.0 is a set of tools for named entity recognition and classification of chemicals in natural language texts, including trivial names, abbreviations, molecular formulas and IUPAC entities. Since the different classes of relevant entities have rather different naming characteristics, ChemSpot uses a combined approach of employing a Conditional Random Field and a dictionary, as well as pattern-based recognition, a classifier model and several methods for consolidating all annotations. ChemSpot also performs named entity normalization by assigning identifiers from several chemical databases. It achieves an F1 measure of 79.0% on the SCAI corpus.</p>
    </description>


	<param-doc name="mentionlayerName">
      <p> Name of the layer containing the named entities </p>
    </param-doc>
 
    <param-doc name="neFeatureName">
      <p> Name of the feature to access the type of the named entities </p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="CRFModel">
      <p> path to a CRF model file (internal default model file will be used if not provided) </p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="openNLPSentenceModel">
      <p> path to a OpenNLP sentence model file (internal default model file will be used if not provided) </p>
    </param-doc>
      
    <param-doc name="dictionary">
      <p> path to a zipped set of brics dictionary automata (parameter defaults to 'dict.zip' if not provided)" </p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="mapTerms2Ids">
      <p> path to a zipped tab-separated text file representing a map of terms to ids (parameter defaults to 'ids.zip' if not provided) </p>
    </param-doc>
    
    <param-doc name="multiClassModel">
      <p> path to a multi-class model file (parameter defaults to 'multiclass.bin' if not provided) </p>
    </param-doc>

  </module-doc>
</alvisnlp-doc>