<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
Copyright 2016, 2017 Institut National de la Recherche Agronomique

Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
You may obtain a copy of the License at

        http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
limitations under the License.
-->

<alvisnlp-doc author="Robert Bossy" date="2012-04-30" target="org.bibliome.alvisnlp.modules.GeniaWriter">
  <synopsis>
    <p>Writes each section in three files in the BioNLP challenge format.</p>
  </synopsis>

  <module-doc>
    <description>
      <p><this/> writes sections, annotations and tuples in the BioNLP challenge format. Each document will be written into three distinct files with the extensions: <em>txt</em>, <em>a1</em> and <em>a2</em>.</p>
    </description>
  
    <param-doc name="events">
      <p/>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="documentFilter">
      <p>Only process document that satisfy this filter.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="words">
      <p>Word annotations. This expression is evaluated as a list of elements (only annotations are retained) with the current section as the context element.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="entities">
      <p>Entity type / Entities pairs. Expressions are evaluated as a lists of elements (only annotations are retained) with the current section as the context element.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="active">
      <p>This expression is evaluated as a boolean with the corpus as the context element, the module will process the document only if the result is true.</p>
    </param-doc>
      
    <param-doc name="sectionFilter">
      <p>Process only sections that satisfy this filter.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="dependencies">
      <p>Dependency tuples. This expression is evaluated as a list of elements (only tuples are retained) with the current section as the context element.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="fileName">
      <p>Name of the output files prefix. This expression is evaluated as a string with the current section as the context element.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="outputDir">
      <p>Directory where to write files.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="entityForm">
      <p>Surface forms of each entity. This expression is evaluated as a string with the annotation as the context element.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="labelFeature">
      <p>Name of the feature containing the label dependenct.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="sentences">
      <p>Sentence annotations. This expression is evaluated as a list of elements (only annotations are retained) with the current section as the context element.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="sentenceForm">
      <p>Surface forms of each sentence. This expression is evaluated as a string with the annotation as the context element.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="wordForm">
      <p>Surface forms of each word. This expression is evaluated as a string with the annotation as the context element.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="eventExtra">
      <p>Event extra text.</p>
    </param-doc>
  <param-doc name="userFunctions"><p>Set user functions available for this module. If this module is a sequence, then all compounds inherit its functions.</p></param-doc></module-doc>
</alvisnlp-doc>
