<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
Copyright 2016, 2017 Institut National de la Recherche Agronomique

Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
You may obtain a copy of the License at

        http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
limitations under the License.
-->

<alvisnlp-doc author="Robert Bossy" date="2012-04-30" target="org.bibliome.alvisnlp.modules.ccg.CCGParser">
  <synopsis>
    <p>Syntax parsing with <a href="http://svn.ask.it.usyd.edu.au/trac/candc/wiki">CCG Parser</a>.</p>
  </synopsis>

  <module-doc>
    <description>
      <p><this/> applies the <a href="http://svn.ask.it.usyd.edu.au/trac/candc/wiki">CCG Parser</a> to sentences specified as annotations from the <param name="sentenceLayerName"/> layer. Sentence words are specified by annotations in the <param name="wordLayerName"/> layer. For each sentence, only words entirely included in the sentence will be considered; <module name="WoSMig"/> and <module name="SeSMig"/> should create these layers with the appropriate annotations. Additionally CCGParser takes advantage of word POS tag specified in the <param name="posFeatureName"/> feature.</p>
      <p><this/> creates a relation named <param name="relationName"/> in each section and a tuple in this relation for each dependency. This relation is ternary:
      <ol>
	<li><param name="sentenceRole"/>: the first argument is the sentence in which the dependency was found;</li>
	<li><param name="headRole"/>: the second argument is the head word of the dependency;</li>
	<li><param name="dependentRole"/>: the third argument is the dependent word of the dependency.</li>
      </ol>
      <this/> adds to each dependency tuple a feature <param name="linkageNumberFeature"/> with the linkage number to which begongs the tuple, and a feature <param name="dependencyLabelFeature"/> with the label of the dependency.</p>
    </description>
  
  	<param-doc name="maxRuns">
  		<p>Maximal number of CCG runs.</p>
  	</param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="active">
      <p>This expression is evaluated as a boolean with the corpus as the context element, the module will process the document only if the result is true.</p>
    </param-doc>
      
    <param-doc name="sentenceRole">
      <p>Name of the role that denote the sentence to which belongs a dependency tuple.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="sentenceLayerName">
      <p>Name of the layer containing sentence annotations.</p>
    </param-doc>
    
    <param-doc name="stanfordMarkedUpScript">
      <p>Path to the markedup script for Stanford tagset output. See <a href="http://svn.ask.it.usyd.edu.au/trac/candc/wiki/Biomedical">Biomedical parsing for CCG</a>.</p> 
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="maxSuperCats">
      <p>Maximum number of supercats before the parse explodes (cited from CCG documentation).</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="relationName">
      <p>Name of the relation containing dependencies.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="stanfordScript">
      <p>Post-processing script for Stanford tagset output. See <a href="http://svn.ask.it.usyd.edu.au/trac/candc/wiki/Biomedical">Biomedical parsing for CCG</a>.</p> 
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="wordLayerName">
      <p>Name of the layer containing word annotations.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="posFeatureName">
      <p>Name of the feature containing the word POS tag.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="lpTransformation">
      <p>Either to translate into LP tag-set.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="parserModel">
      <p>Path to the parser model file.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="documentFilter">
      <p>Only process document that satisfy this filter.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="constantRelationFeatures">
      <p>Constant features to add to each relation created by this module</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="formFeatureName">
      <p>Name of the feature containing the word surface form.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="sectionFilter">
      <p>Process only sections that satisfy this filter.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="sentenceFilter">
      <p>Process only sentences that satisfy this filter.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="headRole">
      <p>Name of the role that denote the head word in the dependency tuple.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="labelFeatureName">
      <p>Name of the feature containing the dependency label.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="executable">
      <p>Path to the CCG Parser executable.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="dependentRole">
      <p>Name of the role that denote the dependent word in the dependency tuple.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="superModel">
      <p>Path to the CCG supertagger model file.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="constantTupleFeatures">
      <p>Constant features to add to each tuple created by this module</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="internalEncoding">
      <p>Character encoding of CCG tools input and output.</p>
    </param-doc>
  <param-doc name="userFunctions"><p>Set user functions available for this module. If this module is a sequence, then all compounds inherit its functions.</p></param-doc></module-doc>
</alvisnlp-doc>
