<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
Copyright 2016, 2017 Institut National de la Recherche Agronomique

Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
You may obtain a copy of the License at

        http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
limitations under the License.
-->

<alvisnlp-doc author="Robert Bossy" date="2012-04-30" target="org.bibliome.alvisnlp.converters.SourceStreamParamConverter">
  <synopsis>
    <p>Converts into a data source.</p>
  </synopsis>

  <converter-doc>
    <string-conversion>
      <p>The data source takes either the form of a file/directory path, or an URL. The following protocols are recognized:
      <ul>
	<li><em>file</em>: the data is in the specified regular file path;</li>
	<li><em>dir</em>: the data is in several files in the specified directory path, if the specified path is a regular file the it behaves like <em>file</em>;</li>
	<li><em>stream</em>: the data comes from the AlvisNLP/ML standard input, the host part of the URI must be "stdin" (<em>stream://stdin</em>);</li>
	<li><em>resource</em>: the data is embedded with the AlvisNLP/ML distribution, the host and directory part of the URL specifies the resource to be used: each module should document which suitable resources are available;</li>
	<li><em>http</em>, <em>https</em>, <em>ftp</em> ...: the data is at the specified URL, AlvisNLP/ML will fetch the data across the net.</li>
      </ul>
      If an absolute or relative path is specified, then <em>dir</em> is assumed.
      Relative paths are relative to the current working directory.
      </p>
    </string-conversion>
  
    <xml-conversion>
      <p>
	<xverb><param value="URL"/></xverb>
	or
	<xverb><param file="URL"/></xverb>
	or
	<xverb><param path="URL"/></xverb>
	or
	<xverb><param url="URL"/></xverb>
	or
	<xverb><param href="URL"/></xverb>
	or
	<xverb><param dir="URL"/></xverb>
	or
	<xverb><param resource="URL"/></xverb>
	or
	<xverb><param>URL</param></xverb>
	<em>URL</em> is converted as described in the string conversion.
	All different forms are equivalent; the name of the used attribute has no influence on the data source type.
	It is thus perfectly legal to write <xverb><param resource="dir:///path/to/dir"/></xverb>.
	Other attributes allow to specify the data source:
	<ul>
	  <li><em>charset</em>: specifies the character encoding of the data ("UTF-8" by default);</li>
	  <li><em>encoding</em>: same as above;</li>
	  <li><em>filter</em>: a regular expression that specifies which files to read for the <em>dir</em> scheme (no filter by default);</li>
	  <li><em>fullNameFilter</em>: a boolean that specifies if the filter applies to the full name of the files in the directory (false by default: the filter applies to the file name);</li>
	  <li><em>wholeMatch</em>: a boolean that specifies if the filter must match the entire name (or full name) of the file in the directory (false by default: the regular expression is searched within the file name);</li>
	  <li><em>recursive</em>: a boolean that specifies if sub-directories should be read in the <em>dir</em> scheme (false by default);</li>
	  <li><em>compression</em>: compression algorithm of the stream: <em>none</em>, <em>gz</em> or <em>gzip</em> (none by default);</li>
	</ul>
      </p>
      <p>If <xverb>param</xverb> has children elements, then each element will be converted as a data source. The resulting is the concatenation of all data sources.</p>
    </xml-conversion>
  </converter-doc>
</alvisnlp-doc>
