<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
Copyright 2016, 2017 Institut National de la Recherche Agronomique

Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
You may obtain a copy of the License at

        http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
limitations under the License.
-->

<alvisnlp-doc author="Robert Bossy" date="2010-10-28">
  <synopsis>
    <p>Converts into an array of acions for <module name="PatternMatcher"/>.</p>
  </synopsis>
  <converter-doc>
    <string-conversion>
      <p>String conversion is not available for this type.</p>
    </string-conversion>
    <xml-conversion>
      <p>The parameter element accepts any number of children elements. Each child element is converted into a single action. Available aactions are:
      <ul>
	<li>
	  <xverb><addToLayer group="GROUP_NAME" layer="LAYER_NAME"/></xverb>:
	  add all annotations in <em>GROUP</em> sub-pattern to the layer specified by <em>LAYER_NAME</em>. If the <em>group</em> attribute is not specified, then add all annotations in the match.
	</li>
	<li>
	  <xverb><createAnnotation group="GROUP_NAME" layer="LAYER_NAME" features="FEATURES"/></xverb>:
	  create an annotation that spans over the <em>GROUP</em> sub-pattern. If the <em>group</em> attribute is not specified, then the created annotation spans over the whole match. The created annotation is added to the layer <em>LAYER_NAME</em> and the features specified in <em>FEATURES</em> are added. The features follow the syntax described in the string conversion of <converter name="Mapping"/>.
	</li>
	<li>
	  <xverb><removeAnnotations group="GROUP_NAME" layer="LAYER_NAME"/></xverb>:
	  remove all annotations in <em>GROUP</em> sub-pattern from the layer named <em>LAYER_NAME</em>. If the <em>group</em> attribute is not specified, then all annotations of the match are removed. If <em>LAYER_NAME</em> is the same as the matched layer, then annotation removal is effective after all matches have been processed in the layer.
	</li>
	<li>
	  <xverb><setFeatures group="GROUP_NAME" layer="LAYER_NAME" features="FEATURES"/></xverb>:
	  add features to all annotations in <em>GROUP</em> sub-pattern. If the <em>group</em> attribute is not specified, then features are added to all annotations of the match. The features follow the syntax described in the string conversion of <converter name="Mapping"/>.
	</li>
	<li>
	  <xverb><createTuple relation="RELATION_NAME" arguments="ARGS" features="FEATURES"/></xverb>:
	  create a tuple in relation specified by <em>RELATION_NAME</em> for each match. Features specified by <em>FEATURES</em> are added to the created tuple. The features follow the syntax described in the string conversion of <converter name="Mapping"/>. <em>ARGS</em> is a comma separated list of arguments. Each argument must be in the form: <em>ROLE=GROUP</em>, where <em>ROLE</em> is a role name and <em>GROUP</em> is the name of a sub-pattern group. The argument is added with the specified role iff the specified group can be associated with a single annotation: the group matches a sequence of exactly one annotation or the group is the target of a <em>createAnnotation</em> action.
	</li>
      </ul>
      </p>
    </xml-conversion>
  </converter-doc>
</alvisnlp-doc>
