<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
Copyright 2016, 2017 Institut National de la Recherche Agronomique

Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
You may obtain a copy of the License at

        http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
limitations under the License.
-->

<alvisnlp-doc author="Robert Bossy" date="2010-10-28">
  <synopsis>
    <p>Matches a regular expression-like pattern on the sequence of annotations in a given layer.</p>
  </synopsis>
  <module-doc>
    <description>
      <p><this/> searches for <param name="pattern"/> on the sequence of annotations in layer <param name="layerName"/>. Note that in a layer, annotations are sorted in increasing order of start boundary, then decreasing order of end boundary; the order is undefined for annotations with the exact same span.</p>
      <p>For each match, <this/> applies all actions specified by <param name="actions"/>. Each action concerns a sub-group of the pattern, if no sub-group is specified then the action applies to the whole match.</p>
    </description>

    <param-doc name="pattern">
      <p>Pattern to match see <converter name="ElementPattern"/> for pattern syntax.</p>
    </param-doc>

    <param-doc name="constantAnnotationFeatures">
      <p>Features to add to all annotations created by this module, these features are added for all actions that create an annotation.</p>
    </param-doc>

    <param-doc name="constantRelationFeatures">
      <p>Features to add to all relations created by this module, these features are added for all realtions that have been created by an action that creates a tuple.</p>
    </param-doc>
  
    <param-doc name="active">
      <p>This expression is evaluated as a boolean with the corpus as the context element, the module will process the document only if the result is true.</p>
    </param-doc>
    
    <param-doc name="constantTupleFeatures">
      <p>Features to add to all tuples created by this module, these features are added for all actions that create a tuple.</p>
    </param-doc>

    <param-doc name="actions">
      <p>Actions to perform each time the pattern is matched on the annotation sequence. See <converter name="MatchActionArray"/> for all available actions.</p>
    </param-doc>

    <param-doc name="documentFilter">
      <p>Only process documents that satisfy this filter.</p>
    </param-doc>

    <param-doc name="sectionFilter">
      <p>Only process sections that satisfy this filter.</p>
    </param-doc>

    <param-doc name="layerName">
      <p>Match the pattern on the annotations contained in this layer.</p>
    </param-doc>

    <param-doc name="overlappingBehaviour">
      <p>What to do if the layer contains overlapping annotations.</p>
    </param-doc>

    <param-doc name="annotationComparator">
      <p>Comparator to use when removing overlaps.</p>
    </param-doc>
  <param-doc name="userFunctions"><p>Set user functions available for this module. If this module is a sequence, then all compounds inherit its functions.</p></param-doc></module-doc>
</alvisnlp-doc>
